linkedin.com/in/sarahhgrant github.com/sarahgrant11 sarahgrant11.github.io

**Senior data analyst** offering a sharp editorial eye and excellent writing skills. Expert leadership ability with 10+ years of print/digital/tv news experience. Skilled in D3, Leaflet, Tableau, Mapbox, Python, SQL. Deeply knowledgeable about the music industry, digital streaming services and chart analysis. My bylines have appeared in: *Rolling Stone*, *Worth*, *New York Times*, *Playboy*, *Bloomberg Businessweek*, *PORT*, *Billboard*, *SPIN*, *Pitchfork*, the *Village Voice*.

Languages & Aptitudes: Python, Matplotlib, Pandas, JavaScript, D3, Chart, Leaflet, Plotly, Mapbox, GeoJSON, R, SQL, Spotipy, MongoDB, SQLAlchemy, Selenium, Tensorflow, Keras, HTML/CSS, Flask, Bloomberg, Tableau, Git, Hadoop, AWS. Technical Skills: Data Cleaning & Interpretation, Web Scraping, Data Visualization, VADER Sentiment Analysis, ETL, Regression (Linear, Multiple-Linear, SVR, Random Forest), Adobe Suite (Illustrator, Indesign, Photoshop), K4.

#### **PROJECTS**

#### COVID-19'S IMPACT ON THE NBA: https://sarahgrantii.github.io/covid-impact-nba-wnba/

- · Built a machine-learning model using nearly-complete season statistics for the NBA & WNBA to determine probability of a "win."
- Group Project awarded "Most Potential For Impact" by Columbia Engineering admin; presented at CU's Demo Day 2020.
- Tech Environment: D3, Plotly, HTML5, Looping API calling, Bootstrap, Slack, Zoom, GitHub, VSCode, TensorFlow, SDKLearn.

### WHERE ARE PEOPLE HAPPIEST?: GITHUB.COM/SARAHGRANT11/WORLD-HAPPINESS-2020

- · Using World Bank and Kaggle data we created an application and visualizations showing every country's happiness for last six years.
- Data cleaning with python, used Flask app for creating API from SQL database, used D3 for the visualizations.
- Tech Environment: Python, JavaScript, D3, MapBox, Plotly, Leaflet, SQL, Slack, Zoom, GitHub, VSCode.

#### HEALTH RISKS BY STATE: HTTPS://SARAHGRANT11-HEALTH-RISK-D3.NETLIFY.APP/

- Created interactive scatter-plot visualization correlating rates of obesity, smoking status and healthcare access with rates of poverty, household income and age, based on Census data for every U.S. state.
- Tech Environment: D3, Javascript, HTML5, GitHub, VSCode

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## SENIOR EDITOR, BILLBOARD, JULY 2019 - JUNE 2020

- Managed team of 20+ staff reporters and freelancers covering the music business for biweekly print section, The Market.
- Used K4, edited with Google Docs and worked with copyediting and fact-checking teams under tight deadlines.
- · Collaborated weekly with Art/Photo team on the section's custom graphics for the opener and section layout.

### NEWS EDITOR, ROLLING STONE, APRIL 2016 - JULY 2019

- · Led 24-hour assignment desk with team of 10+ staff and freelance reporters in Portland, Chicago, London, Nashville.
- · Assigned, edited and published an average of 20 quick turnaround news stories per day via Slack, CMS, WordPress, Hootsuite.
- · Contributed original reporting, profiles, and analysis to online and print, frequently collaborating with video and graphics teams.

# BUSINESS SCHOOLS REPORTER, BLOOMBERG NEWS, MAY 2015 - APRIL 2016

- Wrote analysis for Bloomberg's Best Business Schools 2016 data package. Wrote daily Game Plan newsletter and weekly infographic
  on how to get a job at an in-demand company, The Cheat Sheet. Several articles in **Top 10 Most Read** on Bloomberg Terminal.
- · Proficient in research via Bloomberg Terminal, WestLaw, PACER, LexisNexis.

# ASSOCIATE PRODUCER, BLOOMBERG TELEVISION, DEC. 2012 - MAY 2015

• Wrote/edited creative short video read-throughs on political and financial news for "Money Clip." Booked and produced news segments for U.S. daytime programming and London morning shows, covering EMEA Markets.

## **LEADERSHIP & PUBLIC SPEAKING**

- By:Larm Global Music Business Conference; Speaker.
- Backstage Pass With Citi, Interview series moderator.
- Rolling Stone Podcast on SiriusXM, Guest Co-Host.
- Step Up Women's Leadership, music business panel.
- Pay It Forward, Co-Chair of youth mentorship program.

### **EDUCATION**

**Columbia University**, Fu School of Engineering — 2020 *Certificate, Data Analytics & Visualization* 

**Johns Hopkins University**, Z.K. Arts & Sciences — 2011 B.A. Writing Seminars & English